I'm here at the Air Mobility Command
Museum on Dover Air Force Base in
Delaware and we're about to go inside
the only C-5 plane open to the public on
display in the entire [music] world. The
C-5 is the largest airlifter in the US
Air Force [music] and one of the largest
aircraft in the world. At 247 ft long
and with a wingspan of over [music] 222
ft, it can carry 281,000
lb of cargo.
>> C-5s, there's 131 of them built total.
There's 52 still in service today.
18 assigned right here at Dover Air
Force Base. They're used to move any
outsized or large amounts of cargo
anywhere in the world. You name it,
it'll take it. You know, anything from a
small pallet full of food to then one
Abrams tanks, helicopters, missiles. It
can take, [music] carry, transport just
about anything. Anything that'll fit.
The cargo bay is open daily. Come on
inside and see all this extra space, all
this room
that can carry all kinds of stuff such
as seven Huey helicopters. It can carry
six full-size buses. If you look up
behind us, we have a replica of the
Wright Flyer. It's the the Wright
brothers' very first airplane. And the
distance that they flew goes from that
airplane all the way up to the front
that flag up there, which is a little
over 119 ft.
So, this airplane, the cargo bay of this
airplane is longer than the Wright
brothers' first flight, believe it or
not.
>> This C-5A Galaxy was assigned to Dover
Air Force Base in 1973
and was the first C-5 retired to a
museum in 2013. This C-5 was also the
only plane to ever launch an ICBM, an
intercontinental ballistic missile. That
1974 feasibility test conducted over the
Pacific Ocean proved that the US could
launch nuclear missiles from the air
during [music] the Cold War.
>> But during the Strategic Arms Limitation
Talks, Uh, we we made a deal with the
Soviets and said, "Hey, uh, there's one
of the many things on the table that we
shook hands and said, let's not go to
war today.
Uh, we have this capability and we'll
use it if we have to."
>> The C-5A Galaxy is now retired, but the
Air Force uses a modernized version
called the C-5M Super Galaxy with more
powerful engines and updated systems.
America's largest airlifter can carry
even more cargo across even greater
distances.
To read more about the C-5 and the
history behind it, head to Business
Insider.